Brice Shatzer

www.BriceShatzer.com

brice.shatzer@gmail.com 319-239-2470

Chicago-based technologist with over a decade of experience building software for businesses of all sizes. Skilled in crafting both delightful user-facing interactions & pragmatic solutions, with a passion for the administrative and organizational processes around the craft of software development.

Tools & Technologies -

- "Vanilla" HTML, CSS, & JavaScript
- JavaScript TypeScript / Flow React / Preact / Svelte / Storybook.js
- **Node.js** *Next.js / Express.js*
- CSS SASS/SCSS/LESS

TailwindCSS / styled-components

- Build Tools Webpack / Babel / Rollup / Vite
 Gulp / Grunt / ESLint / Prettier / PostCSS
- Testing Jest / Mocha / Jasmine / Enzyme / Karma Puppeteer / BrowserStack / LambdaTest
- CI/CD GitHub Actions / CircleCl / Bitbucket
- AWS EC2 / S3 / Lambda / DynamoDB

Recent Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer – W.W. Grainger, Inc.

October 2021 - September 2024

- Part of the Core Engineering team, which collaborated across the 1000+ person engineering organization to design & build system-wide technological solutions that saved over 5,400 hours of engineering work
- Architected, built, and supported initiatives like the Grainger Design System, GCOM Micro Frontend (MFE) Core library, & other internal NPM packages which enabled the migration from a singular, monolithic application to multiple micro frontends
- Provided technical knowledge sharing and guidance to other teams on best practices in React, Next.js, TypeScript, Storybook.js, styled-components, & accessibility (WCAG) and established cross-team technological standards while reducing engineering overhead
- Assisted in the migration of CI/CD providers, helping rewrite CircleCI Orbs to GitHub Actions
- Supported the transition of services from an on-prem to a cloud solution (AWS)
- Worked as part of an independent group to standardize the technical portion of the development interview process across the organization
- Participated in the interview and hiring process for developers; on-boarded, mentored, and supported new hires within our team

Senior Software Engineer - PayPal

July 2020 - August 2021

- Part of the Checkout Integrations team that worked on the company's flagship service which handles \$100+B in payment volumes across 200+ countries for millions of active users a month
- Primarily supported the *JavaScript SDK*, working in Preact, Flow, Storybook.js & Express, enabling anyone to accept payments on their website
- Developed critical "*Pay w/ Venmo*" desktop solution, enabling seamless cross-platform payment experiences for customers and unlocking an entirely new payment source for vendors
- Wrote, curated, and published comprehensive documentation around the various tools, libraries, & SDKs that are both used internally and made available to the open source community

Software Engineer - Onion Inc. | G/O Media

September 2017 - April 2020

- Part of the team that worked on *Kinja*, the CMS powering some of the internet's favorite sites like Gizmodo, Lifehacker, Kotaku, and The Onion; reaching 85-100 million active users a month
- Assisted in a comprehensive platform transformation, migrating core system from Scala with Closure templates and Backbone + Marionette to a modern Isomorphic JavaScript (Express & React) architecture
- Created a **testing utility** that enabled consistent and repeatable performance benchmarking
- Implemented & maintained advertising integrations which optimized delivery & tracking, ensuring high performance and reliability across the platform

Additional Work History

Software Engineer – Doejo

September 2017 - April 2020

- Lead development on various projects at a digital agency specializing in enterprise WordPress VIP solutions for high-profile clients
- Provided technical advisement to various stakeholders throughout the sales and development process
- Served as a resource for junior developers through pair-programming and code reviews
- Handled development of client projects and internal tools across the entire stack

Web Developer II - GoHealth

September 2015 - February 2016

- Created and updated sites used in paid search, display advertising, and affiliate marketing efforts
- Coordinated with external clients to create branded gateways onto the platform
- Generated technical documentation and recommendations for future improvements on multiple legacy code bases

UI/Front-End Developer – Packback

Novemeber 2014 - September 2015

- Designed and implemented responsive views for projects built using AngularJS and Laravel
- Built and maintained the Bower package used for styling across all company projects
- · Provided ad-hoc updates to Laravel API microservices
- Created build processes in both Grunt and Gulp
- · Reviewed and provided guidance for teammates' code within my area of expertise

Web Developer/Designer - Links Technology Solutions

April 2012 - July 2014

- Provided JavaScript development for various projects
- Converted static visual design documents and wireframes to fully functional sites
- Handled occasional graphic design work consisting primarily of asset manipulation/creation
- · Made content updates to existing sites on numerous different platforms and technologies

Content & Technology Staffer – World Fantasy Games

February 2009 - October 2010

- Created requirements documentation and wireframes for the development of multiple mobile applications
- Created multiple user manuals for use by new employees and various other staff
- · Handled technical-based customer service emails
- · Implemented and managed a company-wide email solution on the Google Apps Infrastructure
- Provided ad-hoc graphic design and audio/video production
- Managed content on multiple fantasy sports web sites
- Assisted in managing multiple corporate social media identities

Education

Carthage College – Kenosha, Wisconsin Bachelor of Arts in Communication/Digital Media